<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest News | Dante&#39;s notebook</title>
    <link>https://dante-su.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dante-su.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Latest News</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dante-su.github.io/media/icon_hu7efa9fb1b4c0d8b70215a0799cf2d372_307774_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Latest News</title>
      <link>https://dante-su.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norms</title>
      <link>https://dante-su.github.io/post/24-04-24-norm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dante-su.github.io/post/24-04-24-norm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the field of mathematics, norms are defined for elements within a vector space. Specifically, when the vector space comprises matrices, such norms are referred to as matrix norms. Matrix norms differ from vector norms in that they must also interact with matrix multiplication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;frobenius-norm&#34;&gt;Frobenius norm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;defination&#34;&gt;Defination&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Frobenius norm, sometimes also called the Euclidean norm (a term unfortunately also used for the vector $L^2$-norm), is matrix norm of an m×n matrix A defined as the square root of the sum of the absolute squares of its elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
\Vert A \Vert_{F} = \sqrt{\sum_{i=1}^{m}{\sum_{j=1}^{n}{\vert a_{i,j} \vert^{2}}}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;he Frobenius norm can also be considered as a vector norm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also equal to the square root of the matrix trace of $AA^H$, where $A^H$ is the conjugate transpose, i.e.,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
\Vert A \Vert_{F}=\sqrt{Tr(AA^H)}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Frobenius norm of a matrix m is implemented as Norm[m, &amp;ldquo;Frobenius&amp;rdquo;] and of a vector v as Norm[v, &amp;ldquo;Frobenius&amp;rdquo;].&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning study notes</title>
      <link>https://dante-su.github.io/post/23-12-18-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dante-su.github.io/post/23-12-18-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;fully-connected-layer&#34;&gt;Fully-connected Layer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对于线性回归，每个输入都与每个输出相连，我们将这种变换成为全连接层（fully-connected layer）或称为稠密层（dense layer）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-points-in-deeping-learning&#34;&gt;Key points in deeping learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;机器学习模型中的关键要素是训练数据、损失函数、优化算法，还有模型本身。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;简单性&#34;&gt;简单性&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;简单性的另一个角度是平滑性，即函数不应该对其输入的微小变化敏感。 例如，当我们对图像进行分类时，我们预计向像素添加一些随机噪声应该是基本无影响的。 1995年，克里斯托弗·毕晓普证明了 具有输入噪声的训练等价于Tikhonov正则化 (Bishop, 1995)。 这项工作用数学证实了“要求函数光滑”和“要求函数对输入的随机噪声具有适应性”之间的联系。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;indictors&#34;&gt;Indictors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;psnr&#34;&gt;PSNR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PSNR is short for &amp;lsquo;Peak Signal-to-Noise Ratio&amp;rsquo;,so the higher PSNR means the noise is less and the total performance is better. It is often used in examining image generation algorithm&amp;rsquo;s efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ssim&#34;&gt;SSIM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SSIM is short for &amp;lsquo;Structural Similarity of Image Measures&amp;rsquo;, so the higher SSIM means generated image and initial image is more similar in structure and the performance is better. It is often used in examining image generation algorithm&amp;rsquo;s efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lpips&#34;&gt;LPIPS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LPIPS is short for &amp;lsquo;Learned Perceptual Image Patch Similarity&amp;rsquo;. I some cases, higher LPIPS are suitable for evaluating the diversity of images generated by generative models like GANs, but if we are generating images or comparing images to see how different the original images are from the ones to be compared, lower LPIPS are suitable for that as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difference between processes and threads</title>
      <link>https://dante-su.github.io/post/23-09-28-processed-and-threads/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dante-su.github.io/post/23-09-28-processed-and-threads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zhihu.com/question/25532384/answer/411179772&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ZhiHu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;类似”进程是资源分配的最小单位，线程是CPU调度的最小单位“这样的回答感觉太抽象，都不太容易让人理解。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;做个简单的比喻：进程=火车，线程=车厢&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;线程在进程下行进（单纯的车厢无法运行）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;一个进程可以包含多个线程（一辆火车可以有多个车厢）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;不同进程间数据很难共享（一辆火车上的乘客很难换到另外一辆火车，比如站点换乘）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;同一进程下不同线程间数据很易共享（A车厢换到B车厢很容易）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;进程要比线程消耗更多的计算机资源（采用多列火车相比多个车厢更耗资源）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;进程间不会相互影响，一个线程挂掉将导致整个进程挂掉（一列火车不会影响到另外一列火车，但是如果一列火车上中间的一节车厢着火了，将影响到所有车厢）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;进程可以拓展到多机，进程最多适合多核（不同火车可以开在多个轨道上，同一火车的车厢不能在行进的不同的轨道上）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;进程使用的内存地址可以上锁，即一个线程使用某些共享内存时，其他线程必须等它结束，才能使用这一块内存。（比如火车上的洗手间）－&amp;ldquo;互斥锁&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;进程使用的内存地址可以限定使用量（比如火车上的餐厅，最多只允许多少人进入，如果满了需要在门口等，等有人出来了才能进去）－“信号量”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Dante(me) for contributing to construct this website!</title>
      <link>https://dante-su.github.io/post/23-09-20-construction-this-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dante-su.github.io/post/23-09-20-construction-this-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Dante(me) for contributing to construct this website!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy to see a new version of this notes website. This time, I choose wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s webiste template to renew this notes instead of the old one which is built with the help of gitbook, as gitbook would be no longer updated from 2021, a great pity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This notebook was oringinally set for recording some shell command used in Linux. After the content&amp;rsquo;s being gathered togehter, I started to think that I need a far more efficient way than search it in my massed&amp;amp;messy documents to consult it once I have something need to know when writing code or debugging. So, I construct this webiste for me and also for you, the potential reader who found this website by accidence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
